KYLE J. WRIGHT

Phone: (801) 509-8540 | kylejamwright@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>Kyle Wright</u> | GitHub: <u>kylejw2</u>

SUMMARY

I've been offered hundreds of thousands of dollars in scholarship funds for law school, but once I realized how passionate I am for software development, I declined it all. I'm a young software developer with just over a year of collective experience. From C++ to building RESTful APIs in NodeJS, I love expanding my knowledge on software and exploring unfamiliar topics.

SKILLS

MongoDB

ExpressJs

ReactJS

NodeJS

API

HTML

JavaScript

CSS

EXPERIENCE

ONLINE EVENT CALENDAR

August 2020

- In this online event calendar, users may create an account without worrying that their sensitive information will be leaked because it's encrypted on the backend. With a valid token, users are then directed to their personal calendar. This calendar correctly displays a calendar-view to any month of any year, thanks to an algorithm that I developed.
- If you'd like to see the calendar in action without creating an account, use "<u>test@gmail.com</u>" and "test" for the email and password, respectively, to log in.

Web Development Glossary

August 2020

• In this open-source web development glossary, anybody from the community may study the terms and definitions created by others, or they may help the community by adding their own. The simple UI makes the server-side database communication with the RESTful API quick and smooth.

PORTFOLIO

August 2020

• My portfolio is not only a demonstration of the work I've done, it's also an example landing page that can be adapted to any company. The friendly UI makes page-navigation easy.

FREE-TIME PROJECTS

BRICK BREAKER

JULY 2020

- In this single-player game, a user moves the paddle to keep the ball from reaching the bottom of the screen. Users have three lives in this game and work their way past the levels towards victory.
- To build this game, I used the HTML canvas tag and vanilla JavaScript to manipulate the DOM.

YEDDING

April 2017 - Current

- Yedding is a startup that I'm building with some close friends. Yedding is an online service that connects homeowners looking to make large amounts of quick cash with couples looking for wedding venues. Through our online service, couples find affordable, yet beautiful wedding venues and homeowners find a more lucrative approach to renting their property.
- We're bootstrapping the project, and given that we don't have the funds to pay for developers, I've been given the task of building the website. Once the website is completed, I'll begin the project of building an app for IOS and Android.

VOLUNTEER WORK

Y-Serve, Brigham Young University, Provo, UT Self-Help Homes Volunteer

October 2016 - April 2017

- Dedicated Saturday mornings, totaling more than 50 hours, to help low-income families build their homes.
- Brought friends to experience the joy of service, which led to more than 100 hours of their combined help.

Brigham Young University, Provo, UT

March 2018 - April 2018

Inscape Journal Volunteer Editor

• Analyzed numerous poetry submissions with other staff editors to determine which could be published.

THE CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER-DAY SAINTS, PIRACICABA - SP, BRAZIL

JULY 2018 - MARCH 2020

Volunteer Representative and Executive Secretary

- Strategically avoided paying R\$50,000 (5% of the mission's annual budget) in potential visa-related fines by maintaining a respectable and professional friendship with the Federal Police Department of Brazil.
- Devoted thousands of hours towards serving others.
- Supervised nearly 30 missionaries throughout multiple cities, providing training and performance reviews.

EDUCATION

HELIO TRAINING, DRAPER, UT

June 2020 - September 2020

- Learned how to develop and deploy a full-stack web application integrated with a Restful API handling CRUD features.
- Created more than 65 unique algorithms using JavaScript.

Brigham Young University, Provo, UT

SEPTEMBER 2016 - APRIL 2018

- Earned Bachelor's of Science degree, Magna Cum Laude
- Economics Major—Cumulative GPA: 3.99

SALT LAKE COMMUNITY COLLEGE, TAYLORSVILLE, UT

June 2014 - May 2016

- A.S.- Associates of Science—Cumulative GPA: 4.0
- Earned Associate's Degree prior to graduating high school

Unique Achievements

Bilingual (English and Portuguese)

Law School Admissions Test: 168 (Top 5%)

Entrepreneurship Contest Winner (Competed against more than 150 students)